Preliminary Inventory to the Willmoore Kendall Papers, 1916-2004
Hoover Institution Archives
Willmoore Kendall Papers,
1916-2004
94012
Kendall, Willmoore, 1909-1967
31 manuscript boxes (12.93 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence with Willmoore Kendall, Sr., and Yvona Kendall Mason, father and sister respectively of Willmoore Kendall, relating to American politics, political theory, and conservatism in the United States. Includes both original correspondence and version edited for publication, with accompanying commentary, by Yvona Kendall Mason.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1994.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
United States--Politics and government.; Political science.; Conservatism--United States.; Kendall, Willmoore, 1887-1942.; Mason, Yvona Kendall.
Container List
- Willmoore Kendall original letters to Willmoore Kendall, Sr.
  - 1916-1928 (Box 1)
  - 1929-1933 (Box 2)
  - 1934-1942 (Box 3)
- Willmoore Kendall, Sr., original letters to Willmoore Kendall
  - 1924-1928
  - 1929-1940 (Box 4)
  - 1940-1942 (Box 5)
- Willmoore Kendall original correspondence with Yvona Kendall Mason
  - 1934-1954. Includes papers on building of Kendall house
  - 1955-1966 (Box 6)
- W. A. Oldfather miscellany, 1944
- Yvona Kendall Mason rough draft of edited Kendall family correspondence
  - 1916-1926
  - 1926-1931 (Box 7)
  - 1931-1933 (Box 8)
  - 1934-1938 (Box 9)
- Yvona Kendall Mason finished typescript of edited Kendall family correspondence
  - Chapters 1-2 (To 1926)
  - Chapters 3-11 (1926-1934) (Box 10)
  - Chapters 12-15 (1935-1942) (Box 11)
- Incremental materials (Box 12-31)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described.